

JOHN GREGORY DREW

ENGINEERING DESIGN | SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT SYSTEM ENGINEERING

CONTACT







EDUCATION

MASTER OF ENGINEERING Mechanical Engineering Tennessee State University 2009–2012

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING Mechanical Engineering Vanderbilt University 2005–2009

Usage

SKILLS

Skill

	•
Python	Current
Engineering Design	Current
Django	Current
Django-Rest	Current
Six Sigma Green Belt	Current
OOAD	Current
Agile/Jira	Current
Git	Current
React	2020
Solidworks	2018
ANSI Y-14.5	2017
Testing & Validation	2017
Java	2015
C#	2012

PROFILE

Customer obsessed and motivated with experience in engineering design, software development, and functional safety. Excellent critical thinking, problem solving, and organizational skills. Proactive team collaborator with a safety focused background and proven ability to provide software design solutions. Experienced in advanced quality product development.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Forward-Lane | San Franciso, CA - Remote | 2021-Current

Contracted as Django backend developer to act as liaison for engineering and DevOps. Forward Lane uses powerful AI based technology for wealth management applications.

- Created API's using Django and Rest framework in Docker development environment.
- Interface with front-end developers to test Redux async calls verifying output.
- Authored Jira board issues and features for as project lead point of contact
- Create and approve pull request for accelerated team development.
- Build out React front-end and create video presentations for review.

Software Engineer

Full-Stack N Site, LLC | Remote | 2018-2020

Integral part of API development solutions for a wide range of applications in Python (Django). Key contributor to technology direction and application design. Full-Stack N Site is a startup that engineers web applications for mid-size companies.

- Integrated internal applications with the company tracking system using API best standards.
- Took ownership of existing full-stack development project protecting \$10,000 of contract earnings.
- Launched various Bootstrap based websites on AWS S3, EC2 and CloudFront logging
- Led compatibility troubleshooting efforts for Mac/Linux Docker and Makefile conversion to Windows OS.
- Transitioned websites from AWS S3 buckets to AWS Amplify app to add SSL encryption while reducing costs

System Design Engineer

Ford Motor Company | Livonia, MI | 2015-2018

Lead design and development engineer for front wheel drive transmissions systems for all global vehicle applications. Deliver product designs to production using engineering design software.

- Completed Six Sigma Green Belt training
- Developed fluid fill process using MiniTab Data Analysis software to achieve process capability.
- Used CUSCOR studies to develop system key life tests for electrified propulsion systems.
- Managed 5 programs covering 15 vehicle lines at over 20 different manufacturing.
- Executed testing for electrified powertrain systems to verify system life expectancy.
- Managed and update safety documentation including DFMEA and SCCAF.
- Analyzed measurement data to provide products within design specifications and increasing tool life.

Software Integration Engineer

Juxtopia, LLC | Baltimore, MD - Remote | 2012-2015

Led engineering and software team to design wearable optical mechanical system and integrate operating system. Juxtopia develops mechanical systems to enhance human performance.

- Develop android web services for secure persistent connection to workflow database.
- Integrated Java/android operating system into head mounted display system.
- Performed full integration testing of operating system and services for existing workflows.